siuc.edu 2016-11-19

# Campus Web Privacy Policy | Policies & Procedures | SIU

## SIU Campus Web Privacy Policy Main Content

It is the policy of Southern Illinois University to respect the privacy of all Web site visitors to the extent permitted by law. The University's main Web server does not collect personal information about visitors.

However, we feel you should know that when you access the SIU Web site, the University's Web server automatically gathers information regarding browser type, operating system, IP address and the domain name used by the visitor. SIU may use this information to analyze trends, to create statistics for the purpose of determining technical design specifications and to identify system performance or problem areas.

Personal information that you provide by e-mail or through other online means, such as a response to an inquiry or a request for information, is used only for purposes necessary to serve your requests. This may involve redirecting your inquiry or comment to another person or department better suited to meeting your needs.

SIU will only release personal information, when legally required, to help law enforcement investigations, legal proceedings, or internal investigations of University rule and regulation violations.

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, the University has put into place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Our site may contain links to external Web sites. SIU is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such Web sites.

### Use of Cookies

To improve and personalize your experience on our Site, we store cookies on your computer. A cookie is a piece of text stored on a user's computer by their web browser. Cookies may be used for authentication, storing site preferences, as an identifier for server-based session, etc. Cookies also allow us to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information from you, such as which pages you visited and what links you clicked on.

SIU believes that its use of permanent cookies adds value to users not otherwise available. Specifically, SIU believes that all of the types of information collected, and SIU's use of that information, adds user value. For example, using cookies in this manner allows SIU to provide target content to users of our site.

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policies, send an e-mail to Webmaster. Or write to:

University Communications  
Southern Illinois University Carbondale  
1220 Douglas Drive M/C 6819  
Carbondale, IL 62901  
Phone: (618) 453-2276

If you wish to review or change information gathered about you through an official SIU Web site, you may contact the SIU Webmaster who will assist you in locating the person responsible for that site so that you may make your request for that review or change directly with them.
